skechers.com 2015-08-08

# Privacy Policy - SKECHERS Official Site

Last updated: May 12, 2014. You can view our previous policy here.

SKECHERS USA, Inc. (“SKECHERS”, “we”, “our”) is strongly committed to protecting your privacy and providing a safe online experience for all of our users while offering the highest quality user experience to them. Because we gather certain types of information about and from you in order to fulfill your requests and better serve your needs, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of this information. This Privacy Policy discloses what information we gather, how we use it, how to correct or change it, and what steps we take to safeguard personal information provided to us both online and offline. Please note that some of our websites are subject to separate privacy policies. We encourage you to always check the privacy policy on each website you visit to be sure you understand the privacy policy governing that website. Please read the complete Privacy Policy below, as well as our Terms of Use. Please contact us if you have any questions at:

SKECHERS USA, Inc. Customer Service  
228 Manhattan Beach Blvd.  
Manhattan Beach, CA 90266

800-746-3411 (Mon-Fri 8:00am to 5:00pm Pacific Time)

There are many ways that SKECHERS obtains information from you:

  * Via sign-up on any SKECHERS website
  * From an online or retail purchase
  * From navigational information about where visitors go on our website
  * When you enter a SKECHERS sweepstakes or giveaway
  * When you sign up at a SKECHERS store or SKECHERS outlet
  * Upon signing up at a SKECHERS event
  * When you register for SKECHERS Elite™ program

When you register online to receive our email updates or when you register for the SKECHERS Elite™ program, you will need to provide us with your name, e-mail address, and confirm you are age 13 or older. When you make a purchase through SKECHERS.com, you also will need to give us your billing address, shipping address and telephone number so we can process your payment and contact you in the event of any problems with delivery. If you contact our customer service department, you may need to provide us with additional information so that we can respond to your questions or concerns as completely and thoroughly as possible.

In order to provide users and subscribers with the most efficient and enhanced service and better understand your preferences, we may request your gender, shopping preference and product interest. Whether or not you provide this information is entirely up to you.

We also may collect additional non-personally identifiable information (for example, browser version, IP address) which will concern the general use of our website. The navigational information allows us to see which areas of our website are most visited, and helps us improve the quality of your online experience by recognizing and delivering more of the most desired features and services.

All personal information that we obtain about you will be recorded, used and protected by us in accordance with current data protection legislation and this Privacy Policy. By providing us with your personal information, you consent to us processing this personal information in one or more of the ways described in this Privacy Policy.

We will primarily use your personal information to provide products and services to you, for example:

  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature and to provide you with the relevant products or services (for instance, to deliver a prize you may have won in a contest).
  * To send you information via e-mail about products, offers and news we think could interest you. We only send you this if you have opted-in to receive SKECHERS e-mail messages. By providing us your email address through the SKECHERS website (e.g., by registering to receive our email updates, by registering for the SKECHERS Elite™ program, or by making a purchase or by contacting our customer service department) you are opting-in to receive SKECHERS e-mail messages. 
  * To analyze visits to the website and learn about the interests of our visitors in the aggregate and better understand your personal interests and needs, so we can improve our products and services and deliver the type of content, features and promotions that you are most interested in.

The information obtained from online registration is utilized to improve your shopping experience with SKECHERS by enabling you to obtain a faster checkout for purchases and/or opt-in to receive promotional e-mails, which provide you with the latest and greatest information regarding SKECHERS and its products.

The telephone and credit card number information we ask for when you order online is used only to complete the order, confirm the order and confirm shipment of the order. This information is then stored only for the purposes of faster checkout, and is not used for any other purpose.

Although some browsers offer a "do not track" feature in order for you to request that the websites you visit do not track your online activities, the skechers.com website is not currently set up to respond to do not track signals.

A cookie is a small removable data file that is stored by your web browser on your computer. Cookies are only used by SKECHERS to allow you to use the skechers.com website in the most efficient manner. Cookies allow you to place an order on our website, and allow us to enhance and personalize your online browsing and shopping experience. For example, we use cookies to:

  * Remember the items in your shopping basket
  * Recognize you when you return to our website
  * Analyze visitor behavior

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Please note, however, that by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies, you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our website.

We also work with other companies who use tracking technologies, including web beacons, to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. These companies may collect non-personally identifiable information about your visit to our website about your interaction with our communications, including advertising and e-mails. If you object to web beacons, we recommend that you follow the instructions for deleting existing cookies and disabling future cookies. We will still know how many of our e-mails are opened and we will automatically receive your IP address, a unique identifier for your computer or other access device, but we will not identify you as an individual.

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, SKECHERS does not sell, rent or trade any personal information you provide to us online or at our stores, nor do we share such information with third parties. We may disclose personal information about you to third parties who provide services to us and who agree to maintain the confidentiality of such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and use the information only in connection with the services they provide.

Examples of these services include payment processing and authorization, fraud protection and credit risk reduction, product customization, order fulfillment and shipping, marketing and promotional material distribution, website evaluation, data analysis and, where applicable, data cleansing. We may need to share personal information with these third parties so that they can perform these services; however, we limit the personal information that we give to them and authorize them to use this information only for the purpose of performing those services.

In proceeding with your online order, you agree that both your name and address and those of the delivery name and address (if different) will be checked using third parties such as credit agencies. If you are providing a delivery name and address which is not your own, you must have that person’s permission to give us their personal information and for us to use it for the purposes specified. By providing it, you are saying that you have their permission.

We share aggregated demographic information about our user base with our agents, including agencies or third party vendors so that they can provide marketing analysis and consult on advertising strategies. This information does not identify individual users. We also may share non-personal information (such as the number of users who visited the website during a specific time period or who purchased a specific product through the website) with our marketing partners, advertisers and others from time to time. This information generally is shared in an aggregated form.

We may release personal information if we believe in good faith that: the law or legal process requires it; if we have been advised by counsel; we have received a valid administrative request from a law enforcement agency; or such release is necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of SKECHERS or any of our respective affiliates, business partners, customers or others.

As with any business, it is possible that as our business develops, we might go through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, sale of all or a portion of our assets or buying online stores or other assets. In such transactions, information about customers will likely be transferred. If that happens, your personal information may be disclosed to another company, but that disclosure will be subject to the Privacy Policy in effect.

Personal information submitted to or collected through this website may be stored and/or processed in the United States for the purposes described in this privacy policy. By using SKECHERS products and services (including our website), you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.

From time to time, SKECHERS communicates to customers by e-mail to inform them of changes to SKECHERS.com, special offers that might become available, and other information SKECHERS believes will be of interest to site visitors.

SKECHERS will send e-mails to you only if you opt-in to receiving SKECHERS e-mail messages, and you can easily unsubscribe any time you want by updating your contact preferences on our website or following the instructions contained in the e-mail. Notwithstanding the foregoing, you cannot opt-out of Order Emails as described below. By providing us your email address through the SKECHERS website (e.g., by registering to receive our email updates, or by registering for the SKECHERS Elite™ program, or by making a purchase or by contacting our customer service department) you are opting-in to receive SKECHERS e-mail messages.

SKECHERS also uses your e-mail address to confirm your order and shipment of your order, and respond to any inquiries you make online. Because we have to communicate with you about orders that you choose to place, you cannot opt out of receiving e-mails related to your orders (“Order Emails”).

From time to time, SKECHERS communicates to customers by mobile messages to inform them of changes to SKECHERS.com, special offers that might become available, and other information SKECHERS believe will be of interest to site visitors.

SKECHERS will send mobile messages to you only if you opt-into receiving SKECHERS mobile messages. By opting-in to receive SKECHERS mobile messages you are expressly consenting to receiving such mobile messages.

To unsubscribe from SMS, MMS or other mobile messaging, please follow the instructions in the messages you receive or contact SKECHERS as described below.

SKECHERS takes special care to protect the safety and privacy of children. Our web sites are general audience sites. We do not permit anyone under the age of 13 to register with us. We also do not send e-mail correspondence to anyone who tells us that they are under the age of 13.

Children under the age of 13 should always ask their parents or guardians for permission before providing any contact information to anyone online. We urge parents and guardians to participate in their children’s online activities and use parental control or other web filtering technology to supervise children’s access to the web.

SKECHERS will provide you with access to the personal information you provided to SKECHERS by allowing you to view, update or correct your information. In order to protect your privacy, SKECHERS takes steps to verify your identity before granting you access to your private information or enabling you to make corrections. SKECHERS will accomplish this through the use of passwords and personal data.

SKECHERS employs industry-standard security measures to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. In addition, we utilize a licensed system for credit card authorization and fraud detection. We use industry standard SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encryption to protect the confidentiality of your personal information.

Although we make good faith efforts to store information collected by SKECHERS in a secure operating environment, we cannot guarantee complete security. Information collected by SKECHERS will be maintained for a length of time appropriate to our needs.

You may request to stop receiving electronic communications from SKECHERS anytime. You can choose to cancel e-mails and text messages by updating your contact preferences on our website.

To unsubscribe from SMS, MMS or other mobile messaging, you may also follow the instructions in the messages you receive. Similarly, all e-mails you receive will provide you with information as to how to get off the e-mail mailing list if you so desire.

Alternatively, if you would like to have your name and contact information removed from receiving communications from SKECHERS, please contact us by calling Customer Service at 1.800.746.3411 (Monday - Friday 8am - 5pm PT) or by sending an email to [info@skechers.com](mailto:info@skechers.com?Subject=Unsubscribe%20Request). You may also write to us at:

SKECHERS Customer Service  
228 Manhattan Beach Blvd.  
Manhattan Beach, CA 90266

It takes some time to put opt-outs in effect, so you may still receive electronic communications from SKECHERS for several weeks after your request is received.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, you cannot opt-out of Order Emails as described above.

Please review the site periodically to see any updates to the information provided here. This Privacy Policy was last updated on July 14, 2011. You can view our previous policy here.

Back to Top
